BUSAYO OYEWOLE

Urbanstraße 46, 10967 Berlin, Germany | +491521018661 | busayomioyewole@gmail.com

EDUCATION

MSC Usability Engineering

Hochschule Rhein-Waal Kamp-Lintfort | 2019

BSC Psychology

Obafemi Awolowo University Ile-Ife | 2015

PORTFOLIO

https://busayyyo.github.io

SKILLS

User research, UX analysis,
Design thinking process,
Product management,
Wireframing, Visual design,
Prototyping, Usability testing,
Storytelling, HTML5, CSS3,
Vueis, Git.

LANGUAGES

English | Fluent German | A2

INTERESTS

Innovation, product thinking, product management, interdisciplinary design, storytelling

PROFILE

I am a product designer with backgrounds in psychology and usability engineering. I've had experience designing interactive products such as a B2C fintech AI solution and a B2B e-commerce service. I currently work at Instaff, a startup with the mission to provide short term staffing to companies in Germany. I enjoy working in an interdisciplinary product setting.

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI DESIGNER

INSTAFF & JOBS | BERLIN | FEB 2020 - PRESENT

- Working closely with the product owner to achieve business metrics
- Responsible for the UI & UX results of the product
- Product management of some topics, owning them from conception till implementation and afterwards
- Gathering UX insights through interviews, google analytics etc
- Refining both web and mobile interfaces based on new UX insights & business requirements
- Managing CSS and visual design implementations, ensuring they adhere to designed standards
- Setting metrics for A/B testing

UX DESIGNER

SIEGWERK AG | SIEGBURG | FEB 2019 - NOV 2019

- Worked closely with product owner to achieve business metrics
- Responsible for the UI & UX results of the product
- Refined product based on new UX insights & business requirements

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

FLAQSHIP | KREFELD | APR 2018 - AUG 2018

- Implemented UI designs using technologies such as html, css & Javascript
- Testing and fixing websites for usability, functionality, cross-browser compatibility and responsive issues
- Collaborating with other stakeholders to ensure user-facing features are well implemented

PUBLICATIONS

A designer's guide to git

UX collective Feb, 2020

How to navigate your entry level UX job

UX collective July, 2019

Conversational design

Masters thesis Dec, 2019

FAVORITE UX BOOKS

Design of everyday things, About face, Lean UX, 100 things every designer needs to know about people

INTERACTION DESIGNER

KUDI AI | LAGOS, NIGERIA | JUNE 2016 - SEP 2017

- Responsible for user research, analysis & insights
- Design of product to reflect business and user research
- UX writing
- Conducting usability tests and A/B testing to gain product insights

WEB DESIGNER & COPYWRITER

FREELANCE | LAGOS, NIGERIA | 2013-2016

- Design of web interfaces for clients
- Writing copies for products and brands
- Writing and proofreading marketing memo
- Design and development of websites with wordpress, html and css

VOLUNTEER AND OTHER INTERESTS

Design consultant

AI SATURDAYS AFRICA | LAGOS, NIGERIA | 2019 - Present

 Consulting on products at Al Saturdays, a NGO democratizing Al and data science knowledge in Africa.

Volunteer

Redi School | BERLIN | Winter 2020

- Teaching HTML and CSS to Redi students
- Mentoring

Founder and Managing editor

MILLENNIAL POETS | LOCATION | 2017 - Present

 Founded Millennial poets - a publication on medium for Millennials interested in poetry. I serve as managing editor where I manage a team of volunteers that proofread, edit and publish poetry submissions from Millennials around the globe.